Finding Aid to the Save the Redwoods League photograph collection. 1885-2014
The Bancroft Library
- Series 1: Vertical Files., 1897-2014; cartons 1-8; A box 1; AX box 1, folders 1-20; B box 1, folders 1-15, 17-18; C box 1; D folder 1; F folder 1; H folder 1; NEG boxes 1-5; NEG(gl) boxes 1, 3, 8, 9; NNEG boxes 1-6
  - Symmes, Day W., bequest property -- Ranch., circa 1961?-1971; 2 folders (Carton 8)
    Bulk are snapshots of ranch north of Laytonville.
  - Transamerica Corporation, first tree planting in the Transamerica Park., June 12, 1973 (Carton 8)
    - First tree planted in Transamerica Pyramid Redwood Park, San Francisco., June 12, 1973; BANC PIC 2006.030--PIC; 1 photograph (Carton 8)
      Includes John Chase, Vice President of Corporate Relations, Transamerica Corp.; Tony Guzzardo, Anthony M. Guzzardo & Assoc., Landscape Architect; John Dewitt, Secretary, Save the Redwoods League; Newton B. Drury, President, Save the Redwoods League; Leo Hewlett, President, California Redwood Association; Keith Lanning, Executive Vice President, California Redwood Association.
      Photograph by Action Photo Service, San Francisco.
      This material was selectively digitized from a larger resource or collection. From folder: Transamerica Corporation, first tree planting in the Transamerica Park.
  - Union Lumber Company tree farm., 1968 (Carton 8)
    Tree farm at McCoy Creek. Photographs by Howard King.
  - Van Damme State Park (Mendocino County). (Carton 8)
  - Van Duzen Redwoods State Park (Humboldt County)., 1935, 1969 (Carton 8)
    Includes Georgia Pacific gift of redwoods on the Van Duzen River.
    Includes photographs by David Swanlund, and related negatives by Martin Studio.
    3 related negatives removed to NNEG box 3.
  - Wilder Ranch State Park (Santa Cruz County)., June 7, 1980 (Carton 8)
    Includes Save-the-Redwoods League directors field trip
  - Wilder Ranch State Park -- Balthis photographs., September 2002; 2 folders (Carton 8)
    Photographs by Frank Balthis.
    60 matching and related negatives (35mm negative strips) removed to NEG box 2.
  - Yosemite National Park., circa 1920s-1980s (Carton 8)
    Includes Galen Clark's cabin, Mariposa Grove, Grizzly Giant Tree, Wawona Tree (drive-thru tree) and Hetch Hetchy Lake.
    Includes photographs by Obert, Ralph H. Anderson and Moulin Studios.
    - Galen Clark's cabin, Mariposa Grove, Yosemite National Park., 1920s; BANC PIC 2006.030--PIC; 1 photograph (Carton 8)
      Also identified on back as Mariposa Mountain Lodge.
      Photograph by Santa Barbara Obert.
      This material was selectively digitized from a larger resource or collection. From folder: Yosemite National Park.
  - Yosemite National Park, oversize., circa 1910s-1920s?; 1 photograph (A box 1, Folder 12)
    Wawona Tree.
- Series 2: Humboldt County Photographic Survey., 1900-circa 1965, bulk 1920s-1930s; cartons 9-10; NEG boxes 3, 5; NNEG boxes 3-4,6-9.
  Arranged thematically based on number scheme assigned by Save the Redwoods League.
  Photographic survey of land in Humboldt County, mainly along U.S. Highway 101 (Redwood Highway) corridor, moving from south to north. The bulk of images are of redwood groves, especially in and around Humboldt Redwoods State Park. Includes views of the Eel River, South Fork of Eel River, coastal areas, and a few views in Mendocino County.
  The photographs are identified by a rough number scheme assigned by Save the Redwoods League, from 1 to 12100s. Lower numbers are in the southern part of Humboldt County, and the higher numbers are in the northern part of the county. Numbering schemes 12000s to13000s are subject oriented. Eel River and South Fork of Eel River folders are surveys of the rivers, but the photographs are unnumbered. Some unnumbered, but related photographs were found interfiled with numbered photographs.
  The material arrived at the Bancroft Library either in the form of an album, or foldered loose photographs. Many albums were disbound, and photos removed from pages by Save the Redwoods League. Album pages and loose photographs were foldered together with related photographs and negatives. Albums that arrived at the Bancroft library intact were disbound and foldered by library staff for easier use and conservation purposes.
  The loose photographs are a combination of intact album pages, photographs removed from album pages, and related photographs. Many items are duplicates of images in the albums, and follow the same numbering system as the albums. Many of the original folders these loose items were housed in were identified as, "Project I. Humboldt Redwoods."
  - Photographs from Richardson Grove North to Phillipsville (Excepting Whittemore Grove and including Holbrook Grove), Book I [album]., 1925-1937 (Carton 9)
    Notebook type album that has been disbound and foldered by Bancroft Library staff. Mainly covers area near Garberville. Includes Hartshoots property, Richardson Grove, Redway Bluffs, South Fork of Eel River, Benbow Inn, Yeary Ranch, Buhne-Pratt Tract, highway and bridges.
    Includes photographs by H.C. Tibbitts, Drury, H. Lawton, Patterson, Gabriel Moulin, E.R. Freeman, Martin and McCurry.
    1-109 (Save the Redwoods League numbering scheme). Photographs are not in number order.
    25 matching negatives removed to NNEG box 3 (4x5). 21 matching negatives removed to NNEG box 6 (5x7). 2 matching negatives removed to NNEG box 4 (8x10).
  - Photographs from Richardson Grove North to Phillipsville (Excepting Whittemore Grove and including Holbrook Grove), Book II [album]., 1928-1936 (Carton 9)
    Notebook type album that has been disbound and foldered by Bancroft Library staff. Mainly covers Richardson Grove. Includes campgrounds, people swimming in river, and Percy French on a redwood stump.
    Includes photographs by H.W. Shepherd, E.P. French, E.R. Freeman, Fairchild, Drury, H. L. Gabriel Moulin, H.C. Tibbitts, and William Shoeb.
    110-176-G (Save the Redwoods League numbering scheme).
    9 matching negatives removed to NNEG box 3 (4x5). 18 matching negatives removed to NNEG box 6 (5x7). 4 copy negatives removed to NEG box 5.
  - Southern end of Redwood Highway area in Humboldt County., 1931-1935 (Carton 9)
    Loose photographs, many are duplicates of prints in Richardson to Phillipsville albums. Includes Hartsook property, area near Garberville, Holbrook Grove, Buhne-Pratt Tract, Redway Bluffs, Eel River, Bear Buttes, Redwood Highway and bridges.
    Includes photographs by Drury, H. Lawton, Gabriel Moulin, Martin, E.R. Freeman, Patterson, Russell Angel and Bendore.
    4-179 (Save the Redwoods League numbering scheme).
    8 negatives (4 matching and 4 related) removed to NNEG box 7 (4x5). 3 related negatives removed to NNEG box 6 (5x7). 1 related negative removed to NNEG box 4 (8x10).
  - Photographs in the Whittemore Grove [album]., circa 1927-1932 (Carton 9)
    Notebook type album that has been disbound and foldered. Mainly covers Harris Whittemore Grove, and grove dedication. Includes a few loose photographs found with album.
    Includes photographs by Drury and Schoeb.
    52-116 (Save the Redwoods League numbering scheme). Includes a few loose photographs found with album.
    3 negatives (1 matching and 2 related) shelved as NNEG box 7. 2 matching negatives shelved as NNEG box 6.
  - Fish Creek Grove., 1929-1935 (Carton 9)
    Loose photographs that had been removed from notebook type album titled, "Photographs in the Fish Creek and Franklin K. Lane Groves." Includes Hartsook, Gillogly, Dr. Dungan's cabin, hollow tree in Nelson Grove, Charles B. Alexander Grove, South Fork of Eel River.
    Includes photographs by Howe, Newton B. Drury, Martin and Gabriel Moulin.
    180-189, 1084-1098 (Save the Redwoods League numbering scheme).
    11 negatives (10 matching and 1 related) removed to NNEG box 7. 4 matching negatives removed to NNEG box 6.
  - Franklyn G. Lane Grove., 1924-1938 (Carton 9)
    Loose photographs, some intact album pages and album cover from notebook type album titled, "Photographs in the Fish Creek and Franklin K. Lane Groves." Includes dedication of Lane Grove, campsites, Meese Resort, Alexander Grove and the Redwood Highway.
    Includes photographs by Howe, Newton B. Drury, E.W. James, M.L. Merriam and Gabriel Moulin.
    1001-1074 (Save the Redwoods League numbering scheme). Notebook disbound by Save the Redwoods League.
    4 matching negatives removed to NNEG box 6.
  - Miranda to Myers, Book I [album]., circa 1921-1938 (Carton 9)
    Notebook type album that has been disbound and foldered. Includes Stephen's Grove, Logan Flats, Pioneers Grove, Blair Grove, Honor Grove, Smith and Mains, Bolling Grove, Bolling Grove dedication, picnic grounds, South Fork of Eel River and Landsdale Grove.
    Includes photos by Newton B. Drury, William Schoeb, E.P. French, Tibbitts, Gabriel Moulin and Russell Angel.
    2001-2070 (Save the Redwoods League numbering scheme). Photographs are not in number order.
    25 matching negatives removed to NNEG box 7. 1 matching negative removed to NNEG box 6.
    - Album page with photographs of Bolling Grove dedication, Humboldt Redwoods State Park., circa 1920s; BANC PIC 2006.030--PIC; 1 photograph (Carton 9)
      Top two images are of people gathered around a flag draped monument for the Bolling Grove dedication, Humboldt Redwoods State Park, August 6, 1921. Bottom image is titled, "Romance of the Redwoods."
      Numbered 2049-2051.
      From folder: Miranda to Myers, Book I [album] (3 of 3). This material was selectively digitized from a larger resource or collection.
  - Miranda to Myers, Book II [album]., circa 1928-1939 (Carton 9)
    Notebook type album that has been disbound and foldered. Includes Felton Grove, South Fork of Eel River, Mrs. Andrew G. Griffin Grove, Bridge Creek, William Leon Graves Grove, Stockel Flats, Van Sicklen Grove, Nelson Grove, Standish and Hickey lands, George Jensen Grove and Pioneers Grove.
    Includes photos by George D. Pratt, Moulin, Norman Matthew, Drury, William Schoeb and Russell Angel.
    2072-2133 (Save the Redwoods League numbering scheme).
    21 negatives (19 matching and 2 related) removed to NNEG box 7. 5 negatives (4 matching and 1 related) removed to NNEG box 6.
  - Sim Logan property and Smith and Mains Tract., circa 1930s-1947 (Carton 9)
    Loose photographs that are duplicates of, or related to, images in the Miranda to Myers albums. Includes and South Fork of Eel River.
    Includes photographs by Russell Angel, Martin and Gabriel Moulin.
    2005-2036 (Save the Redwoods League numbering scheme).
    2 matching negatives removed to NNEG box 7.
  - Stockel Flats and University of Michigan Tract, or Hammond gift., 1928-1937, undated (Carton 9)
    Loose photographs that are duplicates of, or related to, images in the Miranda to Myers albums and Myers to Weott album. Includes Bridges Creek, Standish and Hickey lands near Myers, and Myers Ranch.
    Includes photographs by Russell Angel and McCurry.
    2090-2110c, 3017-3024 (Save the Redwoods League numbering scheme).
    7 negatives (1 matching, and 6 related of Stockel, Standish and Hickey, and Felton monument) removed to NNEG box 7. 6 negatives (3 matching, and 2 related of Stockel) removed to NNEG box 6.
  - Myers to Weott [album]., circa 1933-1939 (Carton 9)
    Notebook type album that has been disbound and foldered. 1Includes South Fork of Eel River, Mrs. F.S. Gould in Gould Grove, Mather Grove, Kent Grove, Fleischmann Grove, Boardman Grove, University of Michigan Tract, Reynier land, dedication of William H. Sage Grove, dedication of Solon Williams Grove, Humboldt State Redwoods Park Headquarters, Brenner property, Perrott Grove, Edward R. Hickey Grove and Native Daughters Grove.
    Includes photographs by Martin, Drury, Russell Angel, Moulin, Norman Matthew, Dan R. Hull, William Schoeb and Tibbitts.
    3001-3066 (Save the Redwoods League numbering scheme).
    23 negatives (20 matching, and 3 related of Pacific Lumber Co. land and Perrott Grove) removed to NNEG box 7. 7 negatives (5 matching and 2 related) removed to NNEG box 6.
  - Reynier Lands and Brenner property., circa 1920s-1930s (Carton 9)
    Loose photographs that are duplicates of, or related to, images in the Myers to Weott album. Includes cabins on Reynier land.
    Includes photographs by Thompson and Russell Angel.
    3027-3049 (Save the Redwoods League numbering scheme).
    2 negatives (1 matching and 1 related) removed to NNEG box 6.
  - Sage Unit Number 1 lands., circa 1920s-1964 (Carton 9)
    Loose photographs that are related to images in the Garden Club of America Grove, Children's Forest, Sage Unit #1 album, of Pacific Lumber Company land opposite Weott. Includes South Fork of Eel River.
    Includes photographs by Russell Angel and Newton B. Drury.
    4002-4011 (Save the Redwoods League numbering scheme).
    4 matching negatives removed to NNEG box 7.
  - Garden Club of America Grove, Children's Forest, Kerr Creek., 1930-1936, undated (Carton 9)
    Loose photographs that are duplicates of, or related to, images in the Garden Club of America Grove, Children's Forest, Sage Unit #1 album. Includes Kerr Creek Grove, Kerr Creek Flat, Kerr Creek Peak, Garden Club of America Grove, Children's Forest, South Fork of Eel River and Walden lands.
    Includes photographs by Russell Angel, Drury and Martin Studio.
    4006-4083 (Save the Redwoods League numbering scheme).
    10 negatives (8 matching and 2 related) removed to NNEG box 7.
  - Garden Club of America Grove (Canoe Creek), Children's Forest (Kerr Creek), Sage Unit #1 [album]., 1933-1940 (Carton 9)
    Notebook type album that has been disbound and foldered. Includes Kerr Peak, Kerr Creek Flat, Kerr Creek, Kerr Creek Grove, Walden cut-over lands, Myers, South Fork of Eel River, The Children's Forest, Canoe Creek, Garden Club of America Grove, and view from Grasshopper Lookout. No photos of Sage Unit #1 identified in this album.
    Includes photographs by Russell Angel, Moulin Studios and Drury.
    4034-4068 (Save the Redwoods League numbering scheme).
    11 matching negatives removed to NNEG box 7. 7 matching negatives removed to NNEG box 6.
  - North and South Dyerville Flats, and village of Dyerville, Book I., 1929-1941, undated (Carton 9)
    Loose photographs and album pages. Includes Dugan Grove, Dimond Grove, Big Tree, Percy French, Bull Creek Flat, South Fork of Eel River, Devil's Elbow, Canfield Grove, Founders' Tree and Founders Tree dedication.
    Includes photographs by Russell Angel, Tibbitts, Drury, H. Lawton, William Schoeb, Gabriel Moulin, McCurry and Martin Studio.
    5003-5057 and later 839-929 (Save the Redwoods League numbering schemes). Photographs renumbered as 839-929 and foldered together by Save the Redwoods League staff. Current folder title reflects the original folder title.
  - Dyerville Flats., 1926-1936, undated (Carton 9)
    Loose photographs and some album pages. Bulk of the images are of the South Fork of Eel River. Includes Bull Creek Flat, bird's-eye view of the town of Dyerville, Dugan Grove and California Federation of Women's Clubs Grove.
    Includes photographs by Russell Angel, Gabriel Moulin, Tibbitts, Drury, H. Lawton, E.P. French and G. Linden.
    5001-5071 (Save the Redwoods League numbering scheme).
    9 negatives (7 matching and 2 related) removed to NNEG box 7 (4x5). 2 matching negatives removed to NNEG box 6 (5x7). 1 matching negative removed to NNEG box 4 (8x10).
  - South Fork Station and Camp Grant, Dyerville Flat., 1926, undated (Carton 9)
    Includes railroad and lumber yards.
    Includes photographs by H.S. Lawton and Drury
    5063, 5072-5086 (Save the Redwoods League numbering scheme).
    10 matching negatives removed to NNEG box 6.
  - Dyerville and new Dyerville Bridge., 1928-1936 (Carton 9)
    Loose photographs and some album pages. Includes Redwood Highway and Civilian Conservation Corps camp.
    Includes photographs by Gabriel Moulin, Drury, Martin Studio and E.P. French.
    5091-5094 (Save the Redwoods League numbering scheme).
    11 matching negatives removed to NNEG box 7. 2 negatives (1 matching and 1 related) removed to NNEG box 6.
  - California Federation of Women's Clubs Grove., 1932-1937 (Carton 9)
    Loose photographs and some album pages. Grove in South Dyerville Flat. Includes General W. H. and Edwin R. Dimond Grove.
    Includes photographs by William Schoeb, Drury and Russell Angel.
    5095-5098 (Save the Redwoods League numbering scheme). See also: Jordan Creek.
    6 matching negatives removed to NNEG box 7.
  - Photographs in the Area Acquired from the Pacific Lumber Company on the Bull Creek Side of the River [album]., 1925-1931 (Carton 10)
    Notebook type album that has been disbound and foldered. Includes Secretary of the Interior Hubert Work and party in Bull Creek Flat, grove dedication, and people camping in in the redwoods.
    5101-5193, 5300-5305 (Save the Redwoods League numbering scheme). Photographs are not in number order.
  - Rockefeller Forest: Photographs of property acquired from the Pacific Lumber Company, on the Bull Creek side of the river [album]., circa 1927-1936 (Carton 10)
    Notebook type album that has been disbound and foldered. Note on inside cover of album: Pictures illustrating "A Protection Plan for the Bull Creek Unit of the Canoe Creek Unit (The Garden Club of America Redwood Grove of the Humboldt State Redwood Park," by LC Merriam, in collaboration with Frederick Law Olmsted.
    Images include Bull Creek Flat, Canoe Creek, Redwood Highway and campsites.
    Includes photographs by E.P. French, Russell Angel, William Schoeb, Martin Studios, Newton B. Drury, Tibbitts and W.D. Wilcox.
    5101-5199, 5307-5312 (Save the Redwoods League numbering scheme). Photographs are not in number order.
    5 matching negatives removed to NNEG box 8. 2 matching negatives removed to NNEG box 6.
  - Bull Creek Flat., 1926-1940, undated (Carton 10)
    Loose photographs that are duplicates of, or related to, images in the Photographs in the Area Acquired from the Pacific Lumber Company on the Bull Creek Side of the River," and "Rockefeller Forest: Photographs of property acquired from the Pacific Lumber Company, on the Bull Creek side of the river" albums. Includes Rockefeller Forest, Upper Bull Creek Flat, views of Bull Creek from Grasshopper Mountain and people camping.
    Includes photographs by Russell Angle, H.S. Lawton, Tibbitts, M.L. Merriam, Martin Studio and Newton B. Drury.
    4087, 5102-5199, 13087-13088 (Save the Redwoods League numbering scheme).
    2 matching negatives removed to NNEG box 8. 13 matching negatives removed to NNEG box 6.
  - Dyerville to Scotia, Book II [album]., circa 1929-1939, undated (Carton 10)
    Notebook type album that has been disbound and foldered. Includes Pepperwood, Shively area, Jordan Creek, Bear Creek, Charles Newbold Black Grove, Kraus Grove, Engelwood Tract, Avenue of the Giants and logged trees.
    Includes photographs by Angel, Martin, Drury, Moulin, William Schoeb, Tibbitts, Norman Mathew, Freeman Art Studio, McCurry, Martin Studio and Rolla B. Watt.
    5201-5235, 5255, 6002, 6004 (Save the Redwoods League numbering scheme). Photographs are not in number order.
    19 negatives (18 matching and 1 related) removed to NNEG box box 8. 9 negatives removed to NEG box 5. 2 matching negatives removed to NEG box 3.
  - Dyerville to Scotia, Jordan Creek, Book III [album]., 1929-1938, undated (Carton 10)
    Notebook type album that has been disbound and foldered. Includes Atkinson Tree (Spindle Tree), Eel River, Jordan Creek, California Federation of Women's Club Grove, mouth of Chadd Creek, Hite Creek, High Rock, Pacific Lumber Company cutting near Englewood and Percy Brown Grove.
    Includes photographs by Russell Angel, Freeman Art Co., Drury, William Schoeb, Moulin and Martin Studio.
    5209-5254, 6006-6053 (Save the Redwoods League numbering scheme). Photographs are not in number order.
    12 matching negatives removed to NNEG box 8 (4x5). 7 matching negatives removed to NNEG box 6 (5x7). 1 matching negative removed to NNEG box 4 (8x10).
  - Pepperwood and High Rock., 1929-1937, undated (Carton 10)
    Loose photographs that are duplicates of, or related to, images in the Dyerville to Scotia, Books II and III albums. Photographs include Bear Creek, High Rock Flats, Shively Bluff area, Avenue of the Giants, Pacific Lumber Company cutting near Englewood.
    Includes photographs by Drury and Gabriel Moulin.
    5202-5232, 6060 (Save the Redwoods League numbering scheme).
    7 matching negatives removed to NNEG box 8. 2 matching negatives removed to NNEG box 6.
  - Photographs of Grove III, Avenue of the Giants (Highway Station D-73 to High Rock)., 1935-1942, undated (Carton 10)
    Appears to have been a notebook type album that was disbound and foldered by Save-the-Redwoods League. Includes Dyerville-Englewood Tract, C.F. Kraus Grove, Charles Newbold Black Grove, Pitzer Grove.
    Includes photographs by Gabriel Moulin, Hanson, E.P. French and William Schoeb.
    5241-5257 (Save the Redwoods League numbering scheme).
    4 matching negatives removed to NEG box 3.
  - Avenue of the Giants, northern end., 1935-1942, undated (Carton 10)
    Loose photographs that are related to "Photographs of Grove III, Avenue of the Giants" and "Dyerville to Scotia" albums. Some photographs are mounted on paper that is similar to the notebook type albums. A couple of photographs are of a road not specifically identified as Avenue of the Giants.
    Includes photographs by Gabriel Moulin and William Schoeb.
    5246-5257 (Save the Redwoods League numbering scheme).
  - Jordan Creek., 1938, undated (Carton 10)
    Loose photographs that are related to and duplicates of images in Dyerville to Scotia, Books II and III albums. Includes California Federation of Women's' Clubs Grove, Spindle Tree, Hite Creek Tract.
    Includes photographs by Newton B. Drury, Martin Studio, Russell Angel, Paul D. Towne and Gabriel Moulin.
    6002-6028 (Save the Redwoods League numbering scheme).
    3 matching negatives removed to NNEG box 8. 1 matching negative removed to NNEG box 6.
  - Upper Bull Creek and Metropolitan Grove., 1924-1962, undated (Carton 10)
    Loose photographs and some album pages. Includes Johnson Prairie, Look Prairie, Giant Tree (Big Tree?), Upper Bull Creek campgrounds, Grasshopper Lookout, Flat Iron Tree and E.P. French at Big Tree.
    Includes photographs by Gabriel Moulin, Lawton, Howe, Martin Studio, Freeman Art Company, Russell Angel, Newton B. Drury and Tibbitts.
    6030-6069 (Save the Redwoods League numbering scheme).
    4 negatives (3 matching and 1 related) removed to NEG box 5 (4x5). 1 matching negative removed to NEG box 3 (5x7). 13 negatives removed to NNEG box 8 (4x5). 3 negatives removed to NNEG box 6 (5x7).
  - Humboldt County coast., circa 1920s-circa 1930s (Carton 10)
    Includes people surf fishing, town of Orick and Redwood Creek Basin, and Trinidad coast.
    Includes photographs by Martin Studio, Drury and Patterson.
    8102-8145 (Save the Redwoods League numbering scheme).
    7 negatives (1 matching and 6 related) removed to NNEG box 8. 64 negatives (4 matching and 60 related) removed to NNEG box 9.
    Almost all of the negatives were removed from an envelope labeled: Trinidad Coast, Patrick's Point and Humboldt Lagoons. They are part of the same number run (8014-8122), except for a few that are unnumbered. The unnumbered 4x5 negatives are dated April 1931.
  - Humboldt redwoods (general)., circa 1920?-1936 (Carton 10)
    Includes Roberts Tract, Bellows land, Stockel land, park administration house.
    Includes photographs by Russell Angel, H.C. Tibbitts and William Schoeb.
    9100-9146 (Save the Redwoods League numbering scheme).